A Guide to the Shelton-Winn-Oliver Family Papers, 1764-1965
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Shelton-Winn-Oliver Family Papers, 1764-1965
Library of Virginia
42149
16.775 cubic feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Various portions of the collection were gifted, lent for copying, and purchased by and from Mary Winn Shelton and William R. Shelton, Jr.
Biographical/Historical Information
Edwin Shelton was born on 5 June 1798. He was the son of John Shelton III (ca. 1750-1798) and Ann Barrett Southall (1760-1830). Edwin Shelton inherited "Rural Plains" in Hanover County, Virginia from his father. He married Sarah Elizabeth Oliver (1810-1887) on 5 September 1827. She was the daughter of Isaac Oliver and Nancy Alexander Austin of "Laurel Meadow" in Hanover County. Edwin Shelton died on 4 November 1874.
Edwin Shelton and Sarah Elizabeth Oliver had nine children. The youngest was Walter Mitchell Shelton, who inherited "Rural Plains." He was born 1 June 1849. On 9 February 1866 he married Roberta "Bertie" Winston Winn (1856-1903). She was the daughter of William Robert Winn and Susan Parke Goodall. Walter Mitchell Shelton died on 11 July 1903. They had eight children, including their eldest William Robert Shelton.
William Robert Shelton was born on 29 January 1877. He was the next to inherit "Rural Plains." He married Maud Elizabeth Greenlee (1884-1949) on 2 June 1915. They ran a landscape business at their home, and called it "Rural Plains Nursery," specializing in the cultivating and growing of boxwoods. He died on 8 September 1958. They had two children: Mary Winn Shelton (1916-1967) and William Robert Shelton, Jr. (b. 1920). The latter was the last to inherit "Rural Plains." He also continued the family landscape business. In 2001, he sold "Rural Plains," and it will be preserved and administered by the National Park Service American Battlefield Protection Program.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1764-1965, of the Shelton, Winn, and Oliver families of Hanover County, Virginia, primarily Jesse Winn (ca. 1788-1849) and his son William R. Winn (b. 1828). Includes correspondence, accounts and receipts, subject files, ledgers, and oversize items.
The correspondence written to Jesse Winn and William R. Winn deal primarily with legal matters. Both were attorneys, and Jesse Winn also served as sheriff of Hanover County. There is also correspondence that is more personal in nature written between members of the Greenlee family, most notably James Hervey Greenlee (1811-1905) of "Turkey Cove," McDowell County, North Carolina. Some of the more notable items in this series are letters written during the Civil War by Mary Eliza Greenlee (1845-1866), as well as John Alexander Flemming (1836-1864) while he was serving in the 49th North Carolina Infantry. There are also letters written by John Mitchell Greenlee and his brother David William Greenlee while they were attending Davidson College in 1869 and 1870. There is correspondence of Maud Greenlee (1884-1949) while she was on a trip to Cuba which include detailed descriptions of Havana, and there is a substantial amount of correspondence of William R. Shelton, Jr. (b. 1920) while he was stationed in the U.S. Navy at Camp Peary during 1944 and 1945.
The accounts and receipts are divided into two groups. Those of Jesse Winn are arranged alphabetically by the name of business or individual to whom money was owed. Those of William R. Winn and others are arranged chronologically by year.
The subject files contain a wide variety of material, and the researcher should consult the inventory to the collection for a complete listing. There are agreements and contracts, bonds and promissory notes, cancelled checks, clippings, two cyphering books, deeds, estate papers, fee bills, guardian accounts, surveys, tax receipts, copies of wills, and other items. There are a large amount of suit papers relating to various cases in which Jesse Winn and William R. Winn were involved, either as attorney and/or sheriff. This series also contains papers relating to the estates of numerous individuals, including John Austin, Jr., Albert C. Blake, Fleming Brown, James Brown, Peter W. Brown, Sarah Camron, Thomas B. Cawthon, Hector Davis, Ellen P. Duke, L. G. Ellyson, Charles P. Goodall, Jane M. Goodall, Meriwether Jones, Henry King, Henry Lefevre, John T. O'Harrow, Isaac Oliver, Michel Picot de Boisfeillet, Fendall Ragland, Jesse Rice, John Richardson, Joanna Robinson, Silas Shelburn, Maud G. Shelton, John Street, Jr., Parke Street, Nelson Thacker, Garland Thompson, Charles Tinsley, Ann S. Vest, Isaac W. Wingfield, Jesse Winn, Peter Winston, Philip H. Winston, and Polly Woodfin. There are copies of wills for the following individuals: James Brown, Walter Coles, John Darracott, Peter Foster, John B. Green, Henry King, John F. Lucord, Austin Morris, Isaac Oliver, Moses Parsons, Parke Street, Louisa A. Thacker, Wyatt Tinsley, Peter Winston, and Richard M. Winston. Also included at the end of this series is a collection of postal covers, envelopes, stamps, and cancels.
The oversize series also contains a variety of material, and the researcher should consult the inventory to the collection for a complete listing. Included are a Confederate bond, deeds, maps, plats and surveys, Roosevelt/Garner election posters, an 1864 issue of The Soldier's Visitor, an 1823 issue of The Western Carolinian, a copy of the will of Walter Coles (1815), and other items.
The ledgers consist of five account books and day books for mercantile stores owned by John, James, and Benjamin Oliver and Benjamin Oliver, Jr. They contain entries for sale of clothing, liquor, building materials, food stuffs, cooking supplies, and other sundry goods to customers. They also mention tobacco and wheat sales and shipments. There are also some entries for the firm Brand and Oliver. Included are: Daybook, 13 May 1799-3 June 1800, of a Caroline County store owned by John and Benjamin Oliver; Account book, 1790-1791, for James and Benjamin Oliver's Hanover County store; Daybook, 21 October 1790-10 November 1791, 1 November 1794-12 February 1796, for a Hanover County store owned by James and Benjamin Oliver; Daybook, 15 November 1794-29 June 1797, for a Caroline County store owned by James and Benjmain Oliver; and Ledger A, 1794-1812, for James and Benjamin Oliver's Caroline County store. There is also an account and memorandum book, 1829-1851, belonging to James Hervey Greenlee.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: I. Correspondence. II. Accounts and Receipts. III. Subject Files. IV. Ledgers. V. Oversize.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1804-1965 (Box 1-4)
  - 1802 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1804 (Box 1, Folder 1a)
  - 1807 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1813 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1816 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1817 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1818 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1819 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1821 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1822 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1824 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1825 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1826 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1827 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1828 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1829 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1831 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1833 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1834 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1835 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 1836 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 1837 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 1838 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 1839 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 1840 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1841 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 1842 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 1843 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1844 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 1845 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1846 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 1847 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1848 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 1849 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 1850 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 1851 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 1852 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 1853 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 1854 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 1855 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 1856 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 1857 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - 1858 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 1859 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - 1860 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - 1861 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - 1862 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - 1863 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - 1864 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - 1865 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - 1866 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - 1867 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - 1868 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - 1869 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - 1870 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1871 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1872 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1873 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1874 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1875 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1876 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1882 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1887 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1888 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1892 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1896 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1897 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1898 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1899 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1900 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1901 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1902 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1904 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1905 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1906 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1907 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1908 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1909 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1910 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1911 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1913 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1914 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1915 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1916 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1917 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1918 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1919 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1920 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 1921 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1923 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 1924 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 1925 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 1927 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 1928 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 1929 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 1930 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 1931 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 1932 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 1934 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 1935 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 1936 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - 1937 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - 1938 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - 1939 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - 1940 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - 1941 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - 1942 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - 1944 (May) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1944 (July) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1944 (August) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1944 (September) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1944 (October) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1944 (November) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1944 (December) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1945 (January) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1945 (February) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1945 (March) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1945 (April) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1945 (May) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1945 (June) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1945 (July) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1945 (August) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1945 (September) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1945 (October) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1945 (November) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1945 (December) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1946 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9a)
  - 1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1952 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - 1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - 1956 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - 1958 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - 1959 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1960 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1962 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - 1965 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - n.d. (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - Fragments - Dr. Thomas Pollard (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Fragments - Frances A. Richardson (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Fragments - Mosby Sheppard (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Fragments - Thomas Wiley (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Fragments - William M. Wingfield (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Fragments - Jesse Winn (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Fragments - William R. Winn (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Accounts and Receipts, 1803-1961 (Box 5-8)
  - Account Book, 1865-1868 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Account Book, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and Receipts - John Winn (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - A (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - B (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - C (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - D (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - E (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - F (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - G (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - H (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - J (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - K (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - L (Box 5, Folder 14a)
  - M (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - N (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - O (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - P (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Q (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - R (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - S (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - T (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - V (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - W (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Y (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - 1803 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - 1806 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1814 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - 1817 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - 1819 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 1823 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - 1826 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 1827 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - 1828 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - 1829 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - 1830 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - 1831 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - 1832 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - 1833 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - 1834 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - 1835 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - 1836 (Box 6, Folder 24a)
  - 1837 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - 1838 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - 1839 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - 1840 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - 1841 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 1842 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 1843 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - 1845 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - 1846 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - 1847 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - 1849 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - 1850-1851 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - 1852 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - 1853 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - 1854 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1855 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - 1856 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1857 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 1857-1858 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - 1858 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 1859 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - 1860 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1860-1861 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1861 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1862 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1863 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 1864 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - 1865-1866 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - 1867 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1868 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 1869 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1870 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 1871 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1872 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1873 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1874 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1875 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1876 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1890-1902 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1906 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1910 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1926 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1949 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1951 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - 1953 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - 1958 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - 1960 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1961 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - n.d. (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Subject Files. (Box 9-32)
  - Absentees from Company (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Acree vs. Acree admr. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Affidavits (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Agreements and Contracts (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - William Allen's Estate; E.W. Allen; Henry Tucker; R.H. Allen; L.G. Tucker; St. G. Tucker; William N. Barker adm.; Pleasant Tucker (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Allison & Addison (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Almanac (South Carolina), 1844 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - American Bible Union, 1854 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Accounts and Receipts (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Bills, Answers, Decrees, Notices (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Correspondence, 1859 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Correspondence, 1860 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Correspondence, 1861 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Correspondence, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Correspondence, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Correspondence, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Correspondence, 1868 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Corrrespondence, 1869 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Corrrespondence, 1870-1875 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Corrrespondence, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Fee Bills (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Anderson exr. vs. Anderson - Memoranda and Notes (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Anderson, John H. & Patteson, John H. - Receipts, 1868 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Apperson & Dupuy (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Appointment as Militia Captain, 1831 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Arnall (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Atlas, 1824 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Austin, Mary (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Bailey vs. Lowry (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Baker, Mary A. (d. 1868) (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Bank Books (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Batkins, B. M. (Freight Tickets) (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Battlefield Markers Association (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Massena Beazley; Sam Tinsley; W.M. Wingfield; Reuben Johnson (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - William N. Bell & Co. (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Bill of Lading, 1870 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Bills and Receipts for Things Purchased in Richmond, 1815 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Birthday, Christmas, Greeting Cards (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Blackburn (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Blackburn et als vs. Anderson exr. (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Blackwell, Louisa A. (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Walter D. Blair & Co. vs. Woltz (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Blanton (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Blunt, Temple J. (William Perkins) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Board of Agriculture - Hanover County, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Board of Supervisors - Hanover County (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1790-1799 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1800-1809 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1810-1819 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1820-1829 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1830-1839 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1840-1849 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1850-1859 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1860-1869 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1870-1879 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, 1903, 1910-1919 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Bonds and Promissory Notes, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Bonds Paid Off (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Books Used by Merchants in Foreign and Domestic Trade, 1792 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Boschen (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - John H. Boschen & Son, 1873-1875 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Bosher (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Bosher, R. H. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Bowe vs. VCRR Company; Bowe's admr. vs. Winston's exor.; N.W. Bowe; Bowe vs. Bowe; Hector Bowe; Smith assee. to N. W. Bowe; Mary N. Bowe; H.C. Bowe (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Bowles; McDowell (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Bowles admr. vs. Duggins (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Bowles vs. Lacy (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Boyle vs. Gamble (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bradley vs. Kent (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Braxton (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Breeden & Fox (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Briel vs. Wingfield; Briel vs. Miller; Henry Briel; Heath J. Miller; Shelton & Dyer vs. Miller (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - A. Broaddus trustee of Catherine Honeyman; E. Broaddus vs. Garnett's admr.; W.H. Fox; M.A. Nevins vs. Wm. Gouldin's admr.; R. S. Broaddus; J. E. Broaddus; Thomas B. Garnett (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Broadsides (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Brochures (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Brock, John C. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Brown (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - D.A. Brown vs. R.F. Darracott; Sam Tinsley; D.A. Brown vs. C.B. Stewart (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Brown vs. Sheppard admr. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Buckley, Lawrence - Fee Bills (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Burwell vs. Ellett (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Campaign for County Supervisor, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - W.H. Campbell; Hugh Campbell; James M. Dillard; S.E.H. Campbell; H.B. Campbell; W.J. Carpenter; Campbell & Collins; J.P.H. Campbell; Wingfield vs. Campbell; W.H.B. Campbell; Campbell vs. Campbell (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1831-1855 (Box 11, Folder 17-41)
  - Cancelled Checks, 1856-1951 (Box 12, Folder 1-23)
  - Cardozo, Fourqurean & Co. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Carneal, James N. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Caroline Court (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Carpenter vs. Moody (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Cason et al vs. Cason admr. (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Certificates (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Chickahominy Church (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Childress (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Christian (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Christian vs Christian grdn. (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Christian & White (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Church Programs (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Claims for Damages by Federal Troops, 1862, 1864 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Clay, Henry - Indemnity Bond, 1833 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Clayton, Walter (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Clippings (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Clough et al vs. Clough et al (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Cockrem (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Coleman (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Coleman, Amanda (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Coleman, Charles W. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Collins (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Comfort, Daniel - Deed, 1852-1856 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Commissioner of Accounts - Hanover County (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth vs. Washington (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Confederate Bonds (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Confederate Cover (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Confederate Currency (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Confederate Pass (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Contract - Winston/Burton, 1871 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Cook, W.H. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Corr vs. Corr admr. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Samuel S. Cottrell & Co. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - J.C. Courtney & Son (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Cox, D.B. - Orders (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Cox, Duncan B. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Cox & Leake (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Crenshaw, Nathaniel C. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Crenshaw vs. Crenshaw (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Crenshaw, Winn & Cross (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Cross, Henry G. (Winn & Cross) (Box 13, Folder 26-27)
  - Cross vs. Cross admr. (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Cross vs. Harris et als. (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Cross admr. vs. Lumpkin (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Cross et als vs. Cross admr. (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Cross heirs vs. Cross admr. (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Cross vs. Terrill; Cross adm. vs. Lumpkin; Nathaniel Cross; Mary Cross; A.C. Davis; E.P. Crenshaw vs. Nathaniel Cross; N.H. Davis (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Crouch vs. Davis exr. (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Crump et als vs. Lacy et als. (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Crump, Edmund P.C. (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Crump, Edward P. (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Cuba Trip, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - C.R. Cullen; Mildred Thompson (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Cyphering Book - James H.E. Greenlee, 1828 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Cyphering Book, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Dandridge & Co. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Darracott (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Davis (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Davis, Nathaniel H. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Davis, Robert S. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Deeds, 1764-1829 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Deeds, 1830-1845 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Deeds, 1846-1870 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Deeds, 1870-1922 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Delarne, Lewis (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Diary and Memorandum Book - James H. Greenlee, 1873-1900 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Dickinson (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - W.S. Donnan & Sons (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Donnella (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Doswell, G.W. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Doswell vs. Atkinson (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Doswell vs. Jones et als. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Doswell vs. Loyall et als. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Doswell exrs. vs. Talley (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Duke admr vs. Burnley admr. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Dunn (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Duval et als vs. Ross et als. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - James W. Dyson; Charles T. Dyson (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Election Results, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ellett (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ellett et als vs. Blunt (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Ellett vs. Darracott (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Ellett vs. Taylor (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Ellett, Robert - Orders (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - T.H. Ellett (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Engleking, A. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Estate of John Austin, Jr. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Estate of Albert C. Blake (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Estate of Patsy Bowles (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Estate of Fleming Brown (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Estate of James Brown - Louisa County Land (Clopton) (Box 15, Folder 13-15)
  - Estate of Peter W. Brown (Box 15, Folder 16-18)
  - Estate of Peter Brown - Accounts and Receipts (Vouchers), 1856 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Estate of Peter Brown - Accounts and Receipts (Vouchers), 1858-1859 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Estate of eter Brown - Accounts and Receipts (Vouchers), 1860-1861 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Estate of Sarah Camron (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Estate of Thomas B. Cawthon (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Estate of John Clough (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Estate of Watson Coles (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Estate of C.H. Dabney (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Estate of Hector Davis (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Estate of Nancy Davis (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Estate of Ellen P. Duke (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Estate of L.G. Ellyson (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Estate of Charles P. Goodall (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Estate of Jane M. Goodall (Box 16, Folder 2)